<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AesopsFables</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="fable_1">In a field one summer's day a Grasshopper was hopping about, chirping and singing to its heart's content. An Ant passed by, bearing along with great toil an ear of corn he was taking to the nest.

"Why not come and chat with me," said the Grasshopper, "instead of toiling and moiling in that way?"

"I am helping to lay up food for the winter," said the Ant, "and recommend you to do the same."

"Why bother about winter?" said the Grasshopper; "we have got plenty of food at present."

But the Ant went on its way and continued its toil.

When the winter came the Grasshopper had no food and found itself dying of hunger, while it saw the ants distributing every day corn and grain from the stores they had collected in the summer.

Then the Grasshopper knew: It is best to prepare for the days of necessity.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_horse_hunterand_stag">TheHorseHunterandStag</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_jayandthe_peacock">TheJayandthePeacock</string>
    <string name="fable_6">The Lion in Love - An Aesop's Fable
Moral of Aesops Fable: "Love can tame the wildest"

The Lion in Love Fable
An Aesop's Fable
With a Moral
Aesop's Fable Index

Aesop's Fables



A Lion once fell in love with a beautiful maiden and proposed marriage to her parents.

The old people did not know what to say.

They did not like to give their daughter to the Lion, yet they did not wish to enrage the King of Beasts.

At last the father said:

"We feel highly honoured by your Majesty's proposal, but you see our daughter is a tender young thing, and we fear that in the vehemence of your affection you might possibly do her some injury. Might I venture to suggest that your Majesty should have your claws removed, and your teeth extracted, then we would gladly consider your proposal again."

The Lion was so much in love that he had his claws trimmed and his big teeth taken out.

But when he came again to the parents of the young girl they simply laughed in his face, and bade him do his worst.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_lionandthe_boar">TheLionandtheBoar</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_lionin_love">TheLioninLove</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_lions_share">TheLionsShare</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_milkmaidand_her_pail">TheMilkmaidandHerPail</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_mischievous_dog">TheMischievousDog</string>
    <string name="title_activity_the_manand_his_two_wives">TheManandHisTwoWives</string>
    <string name="fable_a_text">A Man came into a Wood one day with an axe in his hand, and begged all the Trees to give him a small branch which he wanted for a particular purpose.

The Trees were good-natured and gave him one of their branches.

What did the Man do but fix it into the axe head, and soon set to work cutting down tree after tree.

Then the Trees saw how foolish they had been in giving their enemy the means of destroying themselves.</string>
    <string name="fable_2">A quarrel had arisen between the Horse and the Stag, so the Horse came to a Hunter to ask his help to take revenge on the Stag.

The Hunter agreed, but said: "If you desire to conquer the Stag, you must permit me to place this piece of iron between your jaws, so that I may guide you with these reins, and allow this saddle to be placed upon your back so that I may keep steady upon you as we follow after the enemy."

The Horse agreed to the conditions, and the Hunter soon saddled and bridled him./n/n

Then with the aid of the Hunter the Horse soon overcame the Stag, and said to the Hunter: "Now, get off, and remove those things from my mouth and back."

"Not so fast, friend," said the Hunter. "I have now got you under bit and spur, and prefer to keep you as you are at present."

 </string>
</resources>
